# Jeudrin Ali Marchena Sanchez

Heredia, Costa Rica | jeudrin@gmail.com | (506) 8564-8885 | linkedin/jeudrin

#### **Profile**

Computer Engineer graduated from Tecnologico de Costa Rica, Java developer since 2012, has experience working with some front-end technologies. Currently works for Proximity as a Java Developer. He is passionate about Technology and Photography, which he practices in his spare time.

## **Technical Skills**

#### **Programming Languages**

Java, Scala, C, C#, C++, Python, ABAP, Apex, Scheme, Prolog

#### Web

JavaScript, React, HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS, JQuery, PHP

#### **Databases**

Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, Oracle, SQQL, MongoDB

#### **Frameworks**

.NET, Spring, AngularJS, Express.js

#### **Additionally**

Swagger, Confluence, Visio, Scrum, Jira, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Maven, Gradle, Hibernate, Apache Tomcat, Node.js, Docker, Git, Kafka

# Design patterns

Facade, Builder, Singleton, MVC

#### **Operative Systems**

Windows, macOS, Linux

#### **CRM**

Salesforce, Microsoft Dynamics, ServiceNow

#### CI/CD

GitLab, Jenkins

#### **AWS**

Elastic Beanstalk, S3, IAM, EC2, Route 53, RDS

# **Professional Experience**

## **Proximity**

Java Developer

#### Responsibilities

- · Prepare reports on the progress of the project
- · Work closely with the client
- $\cdot$  Creation of web services
- · Code documentation
- · Perform unit tests
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Detect and fix errors
- · Analyze and implement requirements
- · Manage databases (diagrams, backups, triggers, stored procedures)
- · Analyze and implement requirements
- · Prepare reports on the progress of the project
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Contribute to all phases of the development cycle

# Technologies Used

 $\cdot \ Git, Spring \ Boot, Hibernate, Java, MySQL, JUnit, Maven, JavaScript, AngularJS, Node.js, Bootstrap, Sass, Amazon \\ Web \ Services (AWS), Linux$ 

#### **Dates**

July 2020 - Present

Java Developer

August 2019 - May 2020

#### Responsibilities

- · Support for a mobile application for product tracking within a Warehouse
- · Development of an independent test module
- · Perform unit and component tests
- · Creation of web services
- · Detect and fix errors
- · Code documentation
- · Analyze and implement requirements
- · Prepare reports on the progress of the project
- · Contribute to all phases of the development cycle
- · Prepare guides and manuals with technical specifications
- · Scrum best practices (collaboration with teammates, commitment to sprint goals, participation in all meetings; standup, demo, sprint planning, prioritize items, tasks delivery on time)

#### Technologies Used

· Java, Scala, Spring Boot, JUnit, Gradle, Docker, Jira, Git, Jenkins, Swagger, Confluence

#### **First Factory**

Full Stack Developer

July 2018 - August 2019

#### Responsibilities

- · Develop new UI
- $\cdot \, \text{Scrum best practices} \,$
- · Code documentation
- · Creation of web services
- $\cdot \ \text{Builds reusable components} \\$
- $\cdot \ \text{Analyze and implement requirements} \\$
- · Writes efficient code through unit tests
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Contribute to all phases of the development cycle
- · Manage databases (diagrams, backups, triggers, stored procedures)
- · Designing and writing scripts using test automation frameworks, such as Selenium and JUnit to solve software problems as a result of the tests

#### Technologies Used

· Git, Spring Boot, Java, Jenkins, Jira, JUnit, Maven, Selenium, React, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, Sass, Swagger, Confluence.

#### Hewlett Packard Enterprise / DXC Technology

Hewlett Packard Enterprise / DXC Technology - Full Stack Developer

September 2016 - July 2018

#### Responsibilities

- · Develop new UI
- · Scrum best practices
- · Code documentation
- · Creation of web services
- · Builds reusable components
- · Analyze and implement requirements
- · Writes efficient code through unit tests
- · Contribute to all phases of the development cycle
- · Manage databases (diagrams, backups, triggers, stored procedures)

#### Technologies Used

· Git, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Java, MySQL, RethinkDB, Jenkins, Jira, JUnit, Maven, Selenium, JavaScript, AngularJS, React, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, Sass, Docker.

Hewlett Packard Enterprise – (Internship) Java Developer

July 2016 - November 2016

### Responsibilities

- · Scrum best practices
- · Creation of web services
- $\cdot \ Analyze \ and \ implement \ requirements$
- $\cdot \ \text{Manage databases (diagrams, backups, triggers, stored procedures)}$

#### Technologies Used

· Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JUnit, Maven, MySQL, Git, Jira

## **Freelance Experience**

**Dates** 

## elmosquetoncr

Full Stack Developer

<u>Responsibilities</u>

April 2020 – Present

- · Prepare reports on the progress of the project
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Work closely with the client
- $\cdot$  Creation of web services
- · Code documentation
- $\cdot \ \text{Perform unit tests}$
- · Detect and fix errors
- · Analyze and implement requirements
- $\cdot \ \text{Manage databases (diagrams, backups, triggers, stored procedures)}$

#### Technologies Used

· Git, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Java, MySQL, JUnit, Maven, JavaScript, AngularJS, Node.js, Bootstrap, Sass, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Linux

#### **Project**

· http://elmosqueton.cr/

#### Condominium

Java Developer

February 2017 - Present

#### Responsibilities

- · Contribute to all phases of the development cycle
- · Prepare reports on the progress of the project
- · Work closely with the client
- · Creation of web services
- · Code documentation
- · Perform unit tests
- · Detect and fix errors
- · Analyze and implement requirements
- · Manage databases (diagrams, backups, triggers, stored procedures)

#### Technologies Used

· Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Git, Jira, MySQL, JUnit, Maven, Linux

#### In All Media

Full Stack Developer

February 2020 - April 2020

#### Responsibilities

- · Creation of web services
- · Work closely with the client
- · Code documentation
- · Scrum best practices
- · Consume and publish events in Kafka
- · Detect and fix errors
- · Analyze and implement requirements
- · Perform unit tests

# Technologies Used

 $\cdot$  Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Git, Jira, Swagger, MySQL, JUnit, Maven, Linux

# **Education**

## Computer Engineering | 2012 - 2016 | Instituto Tecnologico de Costa Rica, San Carlos

· Bachelor's degree

# Languages

- · English (B2+ Intermediate)
- · Spanish, native speaker

#### Reference

#### Ing. Frederid Palacios | (506) 6245-6125

· Software Architect / Tech. Leader at Intertec International